RÉSUMÉ

John Krug

DoB: 12/01/1963

email: jh.krug@gmail.com	Address: Calle Adrián López Iriarte 27, Padul, Granada, 18640, Andalusia, España
Tel: +34 644 334 591. Message first using email or Signal, and we can get together.	LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhkrug GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an experienced information technology professional. I have worked in development, systems integration, support, deployment, data management, and technical documentation, often in leadership roles, in the public utility, private business, and higher education business areas. Most recently, I have been enjoying technical writing using a docs-as-code approach, working remotely, as part of the technical documentation teams first at OutSystems and now, at SUSE.

SKILLS

I have worked occasionally independently, but usually with others, in large and small organizations and teams, in offices, and remotely around the world's time zones. I have been an employee, a director/owner, and manager on different occasions.

I'm currently working in an documentation development team using agile processes, Git, GitHub, Markdown, Slack, and Google Suite tools.

Much of my career at Lancaster was spent data wrangling, working with Oracle, SQL, ETL processes, and Oracle Data Visualization, applying these to library management and analytics. I've also worked with Tableau for visualization.

I have used and integrated many information technologies, databases, networks, and tools over the years. I am familiar with Unix/Linux and the shell and have coded in many languages over the years (Assembly, C, OCCAM, SQL, Lua, Python, Shell, etc., etc.). I have written much technical material and documentation regarding systems integration, automation, and data management. I have learned new technologies, many times, and implemented and integrated them. All this experience has taken place working with others in teams large and small, co-located and remote.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer, SUSE, July 2023 - Present

I'm part of the Rancher cloud products engineering division, working with the documentation team. I write documentation for open-source cloud products working with the engineers and project managers. The projects I'm involved with, so far, are Epinio, and the CNCF projects, Kubewarden and Longhorn. Documentation tools are GitHub, git, vsCode, Docusaurus, and markdown. It's a fully remote role.

Senior Technical Writer, OutSystems, *July 2022 - May 2023*

I joined the Technical Knowledge team at OutSystems to work on product documentation for the OutSystems product suite. I was an agile team lead, updating and writing documentation for the product set. There is daily collaboration with subject matter experts and product owners to move work forwards. The teams worked with Zoom, JIRA and Confluence, Google Drive, markdown, git, VScode, and GitHub. It's a great team and I enjoyed being back in full-time work in a highly technical, client-focused organization. This was a fully remote role.

Library Analytics Consultant, Independent, *May 2017 - July 2022*

From Spain, I worked on behalf of the University of Leeds. This was a fully remote role. I developed a set of Alma and Primo analytics training materials that their staff could use. The CC-licensed training materials website at https://libtics.org (archived at https://libtics.netlify.app, as the domain name expires in 2024) is the result of that work.

The training materials are hosted using Netlify, written using AsciiDoc markup and processed to generate libtics.org using the Antora static site generator. The materials consist of documentation and accompanying video material. The source is at https://gitlab.com/libtics. The project used a docs-as-code approach. This was a fully remote role.

In April 2018, I helped organize and presented at a training workshop on Alma Analytics for UK Ex Libris users in London.

Systems and Analytics Manager, Lancaster University Library, *April 2002 - March 2017*

I spent 15 happy years at Lancaster University Library, starting as the Library Systems Coordinator. The first role was the implementation of the Aleph library management system from Ex Libris. This was used to replace a custom in-house system. Other Ex Libris systems were implemented and integrated; Metalib and SFX from 2004, Primo from 2010, and the new cloud-based library management system, Alma from 2012/13.

For IGeLU[1] and ELUNA[2], I established the first Analytics working group[3]. The group was established to promote the use of Alma Analytics in libraries and to work through issues with Ex Libris regarding analytics products they provided. This involved coordinating the effort of about 14 library professionals around the world in many time zones and building the wider Ex Libris Analytics community at conferences and workshops.

Key achievements: Implementing Aleph, Alma, and Primo. ILM Level 5 Award in leadership and management. First coordinator of the IGeLU and ELUNA Analytics working group. Lancaster University staff award for outstanding achievement.

Technical Director, Xinetica Ltd, 1996 - March 2002

With a small group of colleagues, I started an information systems integration consultancy. Alongside the business management aspects, I did consultancy work and a major systems implementation for ASDA in Leeds. I also worked at the Financial Services Authority, the UK government's financial services regulator, in London, notably on a Y2K migration project. Xinetica did well for a few years then a combination of the first internet bubble collapse and internal divisions closed us down.

Technical Consultant, Protek Ltd, 1994-1996

I worked mainly at North West Water supporting Unix (IBM's AIX) hardware and software infrastructure and developing software on their behalf. I designed and managed a major operating system upgrade that needed to take place over a single weekend and at multiple sites.

Systems Administrator, Barclays de Zoet Wedd, 1992-1993

I supported Sun Microsystems Unix workstations running a variety of financial trading software for the foreign exchange derivatives desk.

Technician, NTSC, 1991

I worked to help the NTSC's[4] efforts in promoting the uses of parallel processing using the INMOS transputer. I followed up on my M.Sc. dissertation work with further work with British Steel in computer vision.

Lance Corporal, British Army, Royal Artillery, 1983-1986

I worked in a mortar locating radar troop. I can drive an armored personnel carrier if necessary. :-)

EDUCATION

1990-1991 - University of Sheffield, M.Sc. Software Systems Technology

1985-1989 - Open University (UK), a variety of undergraduate courses at different levels, mainly mathematics and computing. I never got around to finishing off an undergraduate degree, but the individual course results were good enough to earn a place on an M.Sc. at the University of Sheffield.

REFERENCES

From Masud Khokhar:

https://jhkrug.github.io/public/references/MK-JK-ref.pdf

From David Summers:

https://jhkrug.github.io/public/references/DS-JK-ref.pdf

PORTFOLIO

GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug

GitLab: https://gitlab.com/libtics

A very occasional blog: https://jhkrug.github.io.

FOOTNOTES

- 1 International Group of Ex Libris Users
- 2 Ex Libris Users of North America
- 3 Analytics SIWG (Special Interest Working Group) at https://igelu.org/products-and-initiatives/communities-of-practice/analytics/
- 4 National Transputer Support Centre in Sheffield. A body established with UK government funding to promote parallel processing using the INMOS Transputer. The Transputer was a UK-developed microprocessor with facilities enabling massive parallelism when connected with other transputers.

http://www.chilton-computing.org.uk/inf/transputers/p002.htm